Guide to the Washington Office on Africa Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- WOA Programs, Series IV
  - Lobbying/monitoring activities
    - 1985
      - Anti-Apartheid Act: Lobbying lists, notes (Box 18, Folder 146)
      - Anti-Apartheid Act: Background material; material of other organizations (Box 18, Folder 147)
      - Citizen's Lobby Day Against Apartheid (part of Citizen's Lobby for Peace, Jobs and Justice, April 19-22) (Box 19, Folder 148)
      - Testimony of Jean Sindab before House Committee on Foreign Affairs, Africa Subcommittee and Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs (Box 19, Folder 149)
      - WISC Foreign Policy and Military Spending Task Force (Box 19, Folder 150)
      - Misc. incl. testimony of other WOA staff (Box 19, Folder 151)
    - 1986
      - US aid to UNITA /Angola (Box 19, Folder 152)
      - Sanctions against South Africa (Box 19, Folder 153)
      - Misc. incl. re SA political situation, testimony of Jean Sindab (Box 19, Folder 154)
      - Legislative/ Policy Briefing on Southern Africa - sponsored by Churches' Emergency Committee on Southern Africa -16 Jun 1986 (Box 19, Folder 155)
      - National Protest Day for South African Divestment and Sanctions, 10 Oct 1986 and other actions re. divestment (Box 19, Folder 156)
    - 1987
      - US aid to UNITA/ Angola (Box 20, Folder 157-158)
      - US policy toward Mozambique, RENAMO (Box 20, Folder 159-160)
      - Namibia resolution (Box 20, Folder 161-162)
      - State Department Authorization Bill - Swindall and Burton Amendments vs. ANC and SWAPO (Box 20, Folder 163)
      - Foreign Aid Authorization legislation - SADCC funding (Box 20, Folder 164-165)
      - Sanctions against South Africa (Box 20, Folder 166-167)
      - Sanctions against South Africa (Box 21, Folder 168-169)
      - Outlines of Current and Pending Southern Africa Legislation (Box 21, Folder 170)
      - Political asylum of African individuals (Box 21, Folder 171)
      - Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa (1987 Apr 25) (Box 21, Folder 172)
      - Misc. incl. testimony of Damu Smith before Special Political Committee of UN General Assembly (Box 21, Folder 173)
    - 1988
      - US policy toward Angola (Box 21, Folder 174)
      - US policy toward Mozambique (Box 21, Folder 175)
      - Sanctions against South Africa, incl. testimony of Damu Smith before Congress (Box 21, Folder 176-179)
      - National Anti-Apartheid Action and Lobby Day (16 Jun 1988) (Box 22, Folder 180)
      - Namibia resolutions, hearings (Box 22, Folder 181)
      - Misc. incl. re. children in SA (Box 22, Folder 182)
    - 1989
      - US policy toward Angola (Box 22, Folder 183)
      - Namibia; United Nations Transition Assistance Group (UNTAG) funding (Box 22, Folder 184-186)
      - Bill to limit South African influence and control of US business enterprises (Box 22, Folder 187)
      - Sanctions against South Africa (Box 23, Folder 188-191)
      - "Stand for Truth Until South Africa is Free": "From Pentecost to Soweto" 1989 May 14- Jun 17 and National Lobby Day for Comprehensive Sanctions, 1989 Jun 16 (Box 23, Folder 192)
    - 1990
      - US policy toward Angola (Box 23, Folder 193-194)
      - Misc. incl. overviews of pending legislation, Nelson Mandela resolutions, delegation of Reformed Church leaders (Box 23, Folder 195)
      - Misc. incl. briefing on South Africa, sanctions against SA (Box 23, Folder 196)
    - 1991
      - Sanctions against South Africa (Box 23, Folder 197)
      - US policy toward Angola (Box 23, Folder 198)
- WOA Publications, Series V
  Included here are printed publications with distinctive titles. Many other WOA statements, papers, and press releases are integrated with the program material of Series IV.
  - Action Alert
    - Incl. re. Clark Amendment on Angola; Reagan administration alliance with South Africa; nomination of Herman Nickel, 1981-1982 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Incl. re. Sanctions Bill, U.S. intervention in Angola, 1983-1986 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Incl. re. Aid to Southern Africa; sanctions against South Africa; U.S. intervention in Angola, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Incl. re. sanctions against South Africa; U.S. intervention in Angola, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Incl. re. Namibian independence, sanctions against South Africa, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Incl. re. African National Congress, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Washington Notes on Africa
    - Issues, 1975, 1981-1991 (Box 24, Folder 7-9)
    - Drafts, notes for issues, 1987-1991, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 10-13)
  - Information packets
    - South Africa Information Packet (SAIP), 1985 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - SAIP drafts, notes, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 15-16)
    - South Africa Legislative Packet (with NCCCUSA Africa Office), 1985 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Free Namibia! packet, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Target Angola packet, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Brochures, printed leaflets
    - "Lifting Sanctions: Prescription for Disaster"; "The Case for Restoring Rhodesian Sanctions"; "78 Election Notes on Africa"; "Free Namibia!"; "Zimbabwe: Winning Hearts and Minds"; "Zimbabwe After Lancaster House: What Next?", 1978,1979, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - "Make South Africa an Election Issue"; "Stop the Apartheid Bomb", 1982, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - "The Struggle for Justice"; "Stop Apartheid's War"; "American Steel Jobs and South Africa"; "Election 1984: Stop U.S. Support for Apartheid" (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - "The September 22, 1979 Mystery Flash: Did South Africa Detonate a Nuclear Bomb";"South Africa's Present Economic Situation"; "Stop the Apartheid Bomb" (reprinted);"Apartheid Extended"; "Savimbi and South Africa: No Casual Affair"; "Apartheid's Contras: Rural Terrorism and Mozambique's Struggle for Survival", 1985-1988 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Re. WOA; "Apartheid Extended"; "Natal/KwaZulu, Buthelezi and the ANC, 1990, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Drafts, notes for "Apartheid's Contras..", 1987 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Drafts, notes for publications on reforming apartheid, religious persecution under apartheid (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Drafts, notes for publication "Why boycott South Africa not Nicaragua", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Fact Sheets/ Action Sheets
    - "Southern African and Cuts in U. N. Voluntary Contributions"; "Angola and UNITA"; "RENAMO: Rural Terrorism at Work"; "The Church in South Africa"; "Namibian Churches in the Struggle"; "Trade Unions in Namibia", 1981, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - "Pretoria's Secret War Against the ANC"; "SWAPO: The Liberation Movement of the People of Namibia"; "SADCC: The Southern African Development Coordination Conference"; "Education and Employment Opportunities for Women Under Apartheid", 1991, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Drafts, notes for fact sheets, incl. re. "reform" in South Africa, 1985, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Drafts, notes for fact sheets, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 31)
- Resource/Correspondence Files By Name of Organization, Series VI
  - About My Father's Business; incl. re. African National Congress, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Ad Hoc Group on Southern Africa (Dana Reynolds), 1976 (Box 26, Folder 1a)
  - Africa Development Foundation, 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Africa Faith and Justice Network, 1984-1985 (Box 26, Folder 2a)
  - Africa Peace Committee: See Series IV - Programs
  - African Ambassadors Group, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - African-American Institute, 1976-1988 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - African-American Labor Center, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 4a)
  - African National Congress, 1978-1985 (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
  - African Studies Association, 1973-1981 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Africare, 1983-1989 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Alliance of Black Reformed Christians in Southern Africa (ABRECSA), 1981-1986 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Amandla Freedom Fund, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - American Baptist Churches, 1974-1986 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - American Committee on Africa (see also background material re. Sugar Quota, Series IV, Lobbying Activities -1974), 1969-1985 (Box 26, Folder 12a)
  - American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - American Federation of Labor (AFL-CIO), 1973-1984, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1974, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1976-1987 (Box 26, Folder 16-16a)
  - American Legislative Exchange Council, 1981-1983 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - American Society for Public Administration, 1982-1984 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1974-1982 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Amnesty International - "Conscience and Human Rights: An Amnesty International Curriculum", ca. 1978 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Amnesty International - incl. re. S.A. and Namibians prisoners, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Anti-Apartheid -Bewegung (West Germany), 1982 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement (London), 1980-1985 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Artists for a Free South Africa (Box 28, Folder 24a)
  - Artists United Against Apartheid (Sun City Project), 1985-1987 (Box 28, Folder 24b)
  - Association of Concerned Africa Scholars, 1978-1983 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Association of West European Parliamentarians for Action against Apartheid, 1985-1987 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Belydende Kring (Broederkring) - (South Africa church group), 1979-1986 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Black American Network for Disarmament,Peace and Justice, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Black Leadership Forum, 1982-1986 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Black Sash (Human rights organization in S.A.; incl. info. re. Sheena Duncan), 1985-1988 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Bread for the World, 1981-1989 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Call to Conscience (Emergency Response Network), 1985-1987 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Campaign for Political Rights, 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Campaign to Oppose Bank Loans to South Africa/ Committee to Oppose Bank Loans to South Africa, 1976-1981 (Box 29, Folder 33a, 33b)
  - CANICOR - An Interfaith Council on Corporate Accountability, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1979-1987 (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - Catholic Church (See United States Catholic Conference, and Series VIII, Misc. U.S. Religious Organizations and Churches)
  - Catholic Institute for International Relations (London), 1979-1982 (Box 30, Folder 36)
  - Center for Democracy, 1987-1989 (Box 30, Folder 37)
  - Center for International Policy, 1982-1983 (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - Center for National Security Studies, 1974-1984 (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies, Georgetown University, 1974-1991 (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - Center for Third World Organizing, 1981-1982 (Box 30, Folder 41)
  - Center of Concern, 1983-1991 (Box 30, Folder 42)
  - Christian Aid (London), 1988 (Box 30, Folder 43)
  - Children's Fund for Southern Africa, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 44)
  - Christian Concern for Southern Africa, ca.1978 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Christian Institute of Southern Africa - incl. "Apartheid Morally Unacceptable" by Beyers Naude, 1969-1973 (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - Christian Institute of Southern Africa - incl. reports "South Africa - a Police State?" and "Detention and Detente in Southern Africa", 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - Christian Institute of Southern Africa - incl. summary of CI's contribution to investment debate, 1977-1983 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Church of the Province of Southern Africa (Anglican Church in S.A) - mostly clippings, 1971-1987 (Box 30, Folder 48-49)
  - Church Women United, 1973-1986 (Box 30, Folder 50)
  - Church World Service - incl. Mozambique Emergency Appeal, 1980-1991 (Box 31, Folder 51)
  - Churches' Emergency Committee on Southern Africa, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 51a)
  - Clergy and Laity Concerned, 1973-1989, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 52-53)
  - Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 54)
  - Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, 1983-1988 (Box 31, Folder 55)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 55a)
  - Coalition on Southern Africa, 1988-1989, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 56)
  - Commission of Inquiry into the Espionage Activities of the South African Government in the International University Exchange Fund, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1982-1983 (Box 31, Folder 57)
  - Commonwealth Secretariat: "The Mission to South Africa - The Commonwealth Report", 1986 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Conference in Solidarity with the Liberation Struggles of the Peoples of Southern Africa Continuations Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 31, Folder 58)
  - Congress of South African Trade Unions, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 59)
  - Congressional Black Caucus, 1981, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 60)
  - Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1981-1989 (Box 31, Folder 61)
  - Covert Operations Working Group, 1991-1994 (Box 31, Folder 62)
  - Detainees' Parents Support Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 31, Folder 63)
  - Detainees' Parents Support Committee: Report health care of detainees, 1982 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Dutch Reformed Church in South Africa (Nederduitse Gereformeerde Kerk), 1974-1988 (Box 32, Folder 64-65)
  - Ecumenical Documentation and Information Centre for Eastern and Southern Africa, 1987-1989 (Box 32, Folder 66)
  - Educators Against Racism and Apartheid, 1989-1990 (Box 32, Folder 67)
  - End Conscription Committee/ Campaign, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 68)
  - Episcopal Church, Executive Council, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 68a)
  - Episcopal Churchmen for South Africa, 1968-1985 (Box 32, Folder 69-73)
  - Episcopal Churchpeople for South Africa (See also: YDSL RG102), 1985-1988 (Box 32, Folder 74)
  - Ethics and Public Policy Center, 1982-1983 (Box 32, Folder 75)
  - Evangelical Lutheran Church in America (See also: Series VIII, Misc. U.S. Religious Organizations and Churches.), 1988 (Box 32, Folder 76)
  - Farmer's Group, Inc.: re. B.A.T. Industries South African Activities, ca.1988 (Box 65, Folder 1-5)
  - Federation for Progress, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 77)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 78)
  - Ford Foundation, 1980-1983 (Box 32, Folder 79)
  - Friends Committee on National Legislation, 1981-1985 (Box 32, Folder 80)
  - Friends of the ANC and Frontline States, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 80a)
  - GATT-Fly (Canadian churches for global economic justice), 1978, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 81)
  - Grassroots International, 1985-1986 (Box 33, Folder 82)
  - Gray Panthers, 1977, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 83)
  - Heritage Foundation, 1977-1985 (Box 33, Folder 84)
  - Holland Committee on Southern Africa, 1984-1990 (Box 33, Folder 84a)
  - Human Rights Internet, 1982-1983 (Box 33, Folder 85)
  - Human Rights Political Action Committee, 1982-1985 (Box 33, Folder 85a)
  - Impact Vision, 1987-1988 (Box 33, Folder 86)
  - Inkatha, 1986, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 87)
  - Institute for Food and Development Policy, 1980-1982 (Box 33, Folder 88)
  - Institute for Policy Studies, 1978-1986 (Box 33, Folder 89)
  - Interfaith Action for Economic Justice, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 89a)
  - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, 1975-1982 (Box 33, Folder 90)
  - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility ( See also: Series VIII: Resource File by Topic: Divestment/ Investment), 1983-1992, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 91)
  - International Center for Development Policy, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 92)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions, 1988 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - International Defense and Aid Fund for Southern Africa, 1972-1993 (Box 33, Folder 93)
  - International Fellowship of Reconciliation, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 94)
  - International Freedom Foundation, 1988-1992 (Box 33, Folder 95)
  - International Human Rights Law Group, 1979-1982 (Box 33, Folder 96)
  - International United Black Fund, 1984-1985 (Box 33, Folder 96a)
  - Institute for Black Research: Special report: Unrest in Natal, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Institute on Religion and Democracy, 1981-1983 (Box 34, Folder 97)
  - Investor Responsibility Research Center, 1982, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 98)
  - Investor Responsiblity Research Center: Leaving South Africa: The Impact of U.S. Corporate Disinvestment, 1988 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - John Brown Anti-Klan Committees, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 99)
  - Kairos Workgroup (Christians Against Apartheid), 1984 (Box 34, Folder 100)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1977-1981 (Box 34, Folder 101)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law (incl. from Project Staff in Namibia, 1989-1990), 1982-1990 (Box 34, Folder 102)
  - Lawyers Committee for International Human Rights, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 103)
  - League of Women Voters of the United States, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 104)
  - Lutheran Coalition on Southern Africa, 1979-1980 (Box 34, Folder 105-106)
  - Mennonite Central Committee, 1987, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 107)
  - Michigan Coalition for Human Rights, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 108)
  - Mobilization for Survival, 1982, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 109)
  - Moral Re-Armament, 1970-1982 (Box 34, Folder 110)
  - Mozambique Resource Center, 1983-1987 (Box 34, Folder 111)
  - Namibia Communications Centre, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 112)
  - Namibia Support Fund, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 112a)
  - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 113)
  - National Alliance of Third World Journalists, 1981-1983 (Box 35, Folder 114)
  - National Anti-Imperialist Movement in Solidarity with African Liberation, 1983, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 115)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1974-1979 (Box 35, Folder 116)
  - National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Clubs, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 117)
  - National Black American Law Students Association, 1981-1982 (Box 35, Folder 118)
  - National Black Caucus of Local Elected Officials, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 119)
  - National Black Leadership Roundtable, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 120)
  - National Black Independent Political Party, 1980-1981 (Box 35, Folder 121)
  - National Black Presbyterians United, 1982-1983 (Box 35, Folder 121a)
  - National Black United Front, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 122)
  - National Committee Against Repressive Legislation, 1982-1984 (Box 35, Folder 123)
  - National Conference of Black Lawyers, 1981, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 124)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. - Consultation on Namibia, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 125)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. - Racial Justice Working Group; Africa office, 1982-1986 (Box 35, Folder 126)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A.; Resolution against sanctions; Human Rights Committee, Africa Program; incl. "Profiles of Selected Religious Right Organizations in the USA and their International Outreach", 1987-1990 (Box 35, Folder 127)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., Africa Office: report of consultation - "South Africa - What Does Justice Require", 1991 (Box 35, Folder 127a)
  - National Council of Negro Women, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 128)
  - National Education Association, 1983-1985 (Box 35, Folder 129)
  - National Impact, 1973-1988 (Box 35, Folder 130)
  - National Labor Boycott Shell Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - National League of Cities, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 131)
  - National Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 131a)
  - National Namibia Concerns, 1983-1989 (Box 36, Folder 132)
  - National Rifle Association, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 133)
  - National Student Association, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 134)
  - National Student Coalition Against Racism, 1976-1977 (Box 36, Folder 135)
  - National Student Lobby, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 136)
  - National Urban League, 1976-1987 (Box 36, Folder 137)
  - National Womens Political Caucus, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 138)
  - Nelson Mandela International Reception Committee and other material re. Mandela tour, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 139)
  - Network, a Catholic Social Justice Lobby, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 140)
  - New Alliance Party, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 141)
  - New Democratic Coalition, 1978-1980 (Box 36, Folder 142)
  - Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign, 1984-1987 (Box 36, Folder 143)
  - Organization of African Unity, 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    Resolutions of 22nd Ordinary Session of Council of Ministers; Mogadiscio Declaration; Manifesto on Southern Africa - "Lusaka Manifesto"; Resolutions, Recommendations, and Statements
  - Oxfam America, 1982-1984 (Box 36, Folder 144)
  - Partners for Global Justice, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 145)
  - People Against Racism and the Klan, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 146)
  - People United to Save Humanity (Operation PUSH), 1977-1983 (Box 37, Folder 146a)
  - People's Anti-War Mobilization, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 147)
  - Phelps-Stokes Fund, 1977-1983 (Box 37, Folder 148)
  - Presbyterian Church U.S.A., 1984-1989 (Box 37, Folder 148a)
  - Rainbow Coalition, 1981-1992 (Box 37, Folder 149)
  - Republic of South Africa: Departments of Labour and of Mines - Report of the Commission of Inquiry into Labour Legislation, Part 1, 1979 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Republic of South Africa Parliament documents, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Roosevelt Center for American Policy Studies, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 150)
  - Search for Common Ground, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 151)
  - South Africa Ecumenical Ministry, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 151a)
  - South African Labour Education Project, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 152)
  - Southern Africa Magazine, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 153)
  - Southern Africa Media Center, 1986-1987 (Box 37, Folder 154)
  - Southern Africa Resource Project, 1983-1984 (Box 37, Folder 154a)
  - Southern Africa Support Committee, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 154b)
  - Southern Africa - the imprisoned society (Hanekom case), 1984 (Box 37, Folder 155)
  - Southern Africa Working Group (see Series IV)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 156)
  - Southern Elections Fund, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 157)
  - Study Commission on U.S. Policy Toward Southern Africa (Rockefeller Fdn.), 1979-1982 (Box 37, Folder 158)
  - Svenska Missionsforbundets Ungdom, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 159)
  - Swedish Committee for the Isolation of South Africa, 1985-1987 (Box 37, Folder 160)
  - Swedish Ministry for Foreign Affairs: "Prohibition of Investments in South Africa and Namibia and Other Measures Against Apartheid", 1985 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Swedish People's Parliament Against Apartheid, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 161)
  - Task Force on the Churches and Corporate Responsibility (Canadian), 1989 (Box 37, Folder 161a)
  - Transafrica, 1982-1988 (Box 37, Folder 162)
  - Unification Church, 1981-1984 (Box 38, Folder 163-165)
  - Unitarian Universalist Service Committee/ Unitarian Universalist Association, 1973-1989 (Box 38, Folder 165a)
  - United Church of Christ, 1976-1989 (Box 39, Folder 166)
  - United Methodist Church, 1982- 1988 (Box 39, Folder 167)
  - United Mine Workers, 1973-1985 (Box 39, Folder 167a)
  - United Nations Centre Against Apartheid / Special Committee on Apartheid, 1983-1987 (Box 39, Folder 168)
  - United Nations Centre Against Apartheid: Selection of anti-apartheid cartoons from around the world, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - United Nations Council for Namibia, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 169)
  - United States Catholic Conference, 1979-1994 (Box 39, Folder 170)
  - United States General Accounting Office: reports on implementation of Anti-Apartheid Act, on South Africa trade and investment, 1987-1988 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - United States-South Africa Leader Exchange Program, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 171)
  - United States of America Department of State: The Comprehensive Anti-Apartheid Act of 1986, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 3)